Hello, welcome back to Himler's
History.  In this video, I will teach you how to
write an impressive thesis for
your DBQ and LEQ.  So, if your
brains need to be stimulated with
a set line of reasoning,
then, honey, this is the video
for you.  And just so you know, the
following video is part of a
complete course I've launched called the
AP Essay Intensive Course.  And it covers all
the points of all the rubrics, for
all the writing they will have to
do in AP US, AP Euro and AP World.
So, if you want to check it out
, the link is in the description
below.  And as someone who reads and
rates this nationally, I've
included all the tips and tricks I
know in that course to help you
succeed.  Okay, let's talk about your
thesis.  Now, possibly this is one
of the most important things you
will do in the entire essay, because if
you have a good thesis, you are almost guaranteed to
have a good essay.  I say almost
because, you know, as I like to say,
when you're actually writing
this, you're under pressure.  And when
they're under pressure, they're dumber
than they think.  So yes, I mean,
technically they could still
ruin it if they had a good thesis,
but not you, honey.  Not you.
They are going to learn to write the most
magnificent thesis in the world.  And this
works for LEQ and DBQ.
Now, first of all, let's see what
the rubric says about what constitutes an
acceptable thesis.  It says: answer the
question with a historically defensible thesis or statement
that
establishes a line of reasoning.
To win this point, the thesis must
make a claim that answers the
question rather than just restate or
paraphrase the question.  The thesis should
consist of one or more sentences
located in a single place, either in the
introduction or the conclusion.  And if
they do all that, then they will earn a
point in the rubric.  Alright, as is
our custom, let's break down all that
language.  Basically, it comes down to
this.  Your thesis should be your argument in
miniature.  It will only be one sentence, or at
most two.  And the most important thing to
note, and they're basically doing their
best to help you out
here, is that this is one or two
sentences, and it must make a claim
, and it must be an argument.  It should be
something that someone can
agree or disagree with.  They
tell you clearly there: don't
just repeat the question.  Do you remember
when you were in fourth grade and
learning to write essays, and they
told you to start by turning the
question into a sentence?  For example,
if the question was: "Why did
increased taxes cause the
American Revolution?"  So
you would start your essay like this.  The
tax increase caused the
American Revolution.  And your teacher would
pat you on the head and
say, "Very good, Remy,
golden star."  Well, at AP World, if Remy
does that, whoever reads his essay will take
that golden star, burn it, and
dance on its ashes with
excessive delight.  Because you can't
just repeat the question and
call it a thesis.  Your thesis is an
answer to the question and, as such,
must present an argument.  In a DBQ
or LEQ, you're more likely to see something
like this.  Evaluate the extent to which
increased taxes caused the
American Revolution.  You know, it's
probably more elegant than that
, but you get the idea.  So, in
this case, if I decide to invoke my
fourth-grade self and say that
tax increases caused the
American Revolution, you get no points.  That's what
the question is asking.
The question asks, of all the possible
causes of the revolution, how much
the increase in taxes influenced it.
So, if you read the question carefully,
you'll see that it forces you to make an
argument.  Either the
tax increase was a significant cause,
or it was insignificant and something else was the
main cause.  So that's the
first thing.  Your thesis must present
an argument.  Second, your thesis must
be specific.  I see that many people
miss the point here as well.  For
example, have you ever seen a
haggis?  It is a Scottish delicacy where
minced mutton is
forced into a sheep's stomach
until it is about to burst and
then cooked.  That's what your thesis
should look like.  You want to fill that
sentence with so much evidence that it's about
to burst.  In other words,
actually name the evidence you are going to use
in your essay.  For example, don't just say
that increased taxes were
a significant cause of the
American Revolution.  Instead, say
that the imposition of taxes like the
Stamp Act and the Sugar Act
threatened the colonists' notion of self-government
and were therefore a
significant cause of the
American Revolution.  Specific.  Be specific
.  Name your evidence in the thesis.
Now, what I just gave you is still
a bit simplistic because, in
reality, you're going to use more than one
piece of evidence.  So, for that,
be sure to review the examples in
the notes on what kind of thesis
will get the point and which won't.  Now,
the last thing I want to mention is
how you should structure your thesis.  And
note that the rubric does not limit you to
a specific structure.  So, you
know, do whatever you want.  But
since the thesis is so important
to the construction of your essay,
let me show you how I think you
should do it.  The formula is as
follows.  Despite the counterargument,
due to evidence one and
evidence two, my argument.  Now,
note that this formula does three things
.  Begin with a counterargument.  Every
story has at least two
sides.  And for their argument, they will
present one side.  But here in the
thesis, they will acknowledge that there is another
possible reading of the evidence that
could be argued, but
they are simply not so convinced that it is the
best reading of the evidence.  And this
is not strictly necessary for them to
get the thesis point, but it will
prepare them later to earn the
complexity point.  So, do your
best to start with a
counterargument.  The second thing it
does is force them to name their
evidence, which they will need to
win the point.  And the third thing it does
is force them into an argument that they
also need to win the point.
So let me show you an example
of what this might look like in
practice.  And just for fun,
since I've used an example from
American history, let's use one that can be
applied to both world history and
European history.  The question from the
2019 AP World exam was the
following.  Evaluate the extent to which
the Portuguese transformed
maritime trade in the
Indian Ocean in the 16th century.  Now, here
is the thesis that would win the point.
Although some understand the arrival of
the Portuguese as a
fundamental change in maritime trade in
the Indian Ocean in the 16th century.
There's my counterargument.  Because
the Portuguese never extended
their political control beyond a
few ports.  There's evidence
number one.  And they had to compete
with Indian traders in
regional states like the Ottoman Empire.
There is evidence number two.  His arrival
brought about a modest change at best
.  And that's my argument.
That's a complex and loaded thesis that's about to
explode.  Present a
counterargument.  And it uses
specific historical evidence and establishes a
line of reasoning.  And that, ladies and
gentlemen, is how you write a
thesis.  Great, I hope this
helped.  Here's the link to the
essay writing course, in case you're interested in
that sort of thing.  If this video
helped you and you want me to keep making them,
subscribe and I'll gladly do so.  I'm
Laur.